

San Mateo, CA 650-585-2194 xTonyYu@gmail.com github.com/xTonyYu xtonyyu.github.io/portfolio linkedin.com/in/xtonyyu/

SUMMARY

Goal-oriented, proactive full stack software engineer with a background in financial reporting and data analysis. Experience managing people, building user focused tools, and improving efficiency. Along with empathy, I bring a unique perspective from my prior experiences to engineering team in building innovative and intuitive applications/solutions. My goal is to provide users with positive experiences that make their lives easier.

SKILLS

Technical Skills

- JavaScript (ES6), Node.js, Express, React, Redux, HTML/CSS, JQuery SQL, MongoDB, Mongoose
- Python, Django RESTful APIs

Soft Skills – Empathy, problem solving, cross-functional collaboration and management, effective verbal & written communication

PROJECTS

 Plum & Pear Store and API - Developed MERN e-commerce site with login auth that served both the shop owners and customers. Created Node server API, designed data structure, constructed frontend with React and React router for site navigation. Built user specific shopping cart, ability to "like" the merchandise, and payment functionality.

React, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, Node server API, payment API

<u>Cello shop inventory management app</u> - Built an inventory management app. Developed RESTful back-end API using Express router and middleware, designed data model using MongoDB.
 Constructed summary page using EJS temple and embedded Google chart API.

Express, Node.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, EJS, Bootstrap, Google chart API

- <u>"Wayfayer" travel blog site</u> Created a responsive blog site using Django framework. Built signup and login modal, universal modal close button, add blog, limiting blog text display, automated welcome email.
 Python, Django, DTL, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap
- Responsive online game Created a fast-pace game inspired by 90's Tamagotchi game. Constructed responsive web page with HTML/CSS and plugin. Developed game algorithms using JavaScript.

 JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS
- <u>Skin-care review site</u> Built a product review site in 24 hours by collaborating with UX designers. Created product show page html/EJS template. Designed RESTful API with Express, Node.js, MongoDB
- Plum & Pear tech career path site (personal project, May 2020) Created a site that used plain vanilla JS to create a responsive carousel with cards of various widths.

 JavaScript, HTML, CSS
- Personal Spotify music list update (personal project, Apr 2020) Created web app algorithms using
 React to pull & update playlist via Spotify API.
 React, JavaScript, Spotify API

Tony S. Yu

EXPERIENCE

General Assembly Immersive Program, San Francisco, CA

Jun 2020 – Sep 2020

Full Stack Software Engineer

- Developed and designed applications using programming best practice, technical knowledge (JavaScript, React, Redux, Python, Node.js, MongoDB, SQL, etc.), and optimizing code.
- Leveraged project management and leadership skills along with Agile Development principles to ensure applications are completed on time and met the requirements.
- Completed over 600 hours of programming, projects, and expert-led instruction; gained a working knowledge of software development technologies.

Silicon Valley Bank, Santa Clara, CA

Feb 2015 – Feb 2020

Analysis and Insights Manager

- Responsible for reporting analyses of \$150 billion clients' funds including tracking pre-IPO and IPO
 of technology and life-science industries, product trend, performance, and funding impact
- Slashed processing time in half (3 weeks to 1.5 weeks) by reengineering process flow and practicing Agile Development principles.
- Developed an action driven, user focused UX reporting tool for executives and sales teams by leading and collaborating closely with product and software development teams.

Asset Liability Manager

Sep 2009 – Jan2015

- Implemented new planning software application, engaged team through technical mentoring, and reduced IT support response time.
- Developed and improved dashboards effectiveness by partnering with stakeholders, software development, portfolio, and product teams.
- Effectively communicated analysis and translated technical results to senior management.

JP Morgan Chase, Seattle, WA

2005 - Apr 2009

Modeling Software System Manager

- Responsible for \$300 billion monthly balance sheet modeling process and financial risks.
- Slashed modeling software enhancement turnaround time by 14 days through actively partnering and engaging with stakeholders.
- Directed modeling software development testing plan to be complete on time; developed testing that included optimizing code, functionality, and database.

EDUCATION

General Assembly Immersive Program, Full Stack Software Engineer (Jun – Sep 2020) University of California, Berkeley, completed coursework for M.S. Nuclear Engineering University of California, Berkeley, B.S. Nuclear Engineering